A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia Office Administrative Files, 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia Office Administrative Files 2004-2005
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
2/1/2.072
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access is prohibited for ten years from the date of creation unless special permission is granted by the President's Office. Under the terms of the Virginia Freedom of Information Act (Sec. 2.1-343 (4), the records of the president or other chief executive officer of any state-supported institution of higher education are exempt from the law's access provisions.
Additional access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
These records were transferred from the Office of the President, Madison Hall, University of Virginia, through Peggy S. Pasternak, on July 6, 2007.
Scope and Content
These files constitute the major record series generated by the president of the University of Virginia, John Thomas Casteen, III, ca. 9,900 items (33 Hollinger boxes, ca. 14 linear shelf feet), 2004-2005.
The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office. Major topics include American Council on Education; Association of American Universities; athletics and the NCAA; the Council of Presidents of State-Aided Institutions of Higher Learning in Virgina; development; the General Assembly; the Governor of Virginia's office; the Mariners' Museum; the Medical Center and the Health Services Foundation; Reserve Officers' Training Corps; State Council of Higher Education for Virginia; and Student Affairs.
Arrangement
Both the series and file headings used by the president's office have been retained. Restricted material has been placed in its own series. There are two series: Series I) General Files (Boxes 1-29); Series II) Restricted Files (Boxes 30-33).
Contents List
- Series I: General Files
  - "A" - "Al" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 1:1)
  - "A" - "Al" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 1:2)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - "An" - "Az" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - African-American Affairs, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Alumni Association, 2004 July-September (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Alumni Association, 2004 September-2005 January (Box-folder 1:7)
  - Alumni Association, 2005 January-March (Box-folder 1:8)
  - American Council on Education-General, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:1)
  - American Council on Education-The Presidency, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Architecture, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:3)
  - Art-General, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:4)
  - Art-University Art Museum (Box-folder 2:5)
  - Arts and Sciences, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:6)
  - Association of American Colleges and Universities, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 2:7)
  - Association of American Universities-General, 2004 June-September (Box-folder 3:1)
  - Association of American Universities-General, 2004 November (Box-folder 3:2)
  - Association of American Universities-General, 2004 November-December (Box-folder 3:3)
  - Association of American Universities-General, 2004 December-2005 April (Box-folder 3:4)
  - Association of American Universities-General, 2005 April-June (Box-folder 3:5)
  - Association of American Universities- Meeting, 2004 October 17-19, Folder 1 of 4. (Box-folder 3:6)
  - Association of American Universities- Meeting, 2004 October 17-19, Folder 2 of 4. (Box-folder 4:1)
  - Association of American Universities- Meeting, 2004 October 17-19, Folder 3 of 4. (Box-folder 4:2)
  - Association of American Universities- Meeting, 2004 October 17-19, Folder 4 of 4. (Box-folder 4:3)
  - Association of Governing Boards, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 4:4)
  - Athletics-General, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 4:5)
  - Athletics- ACC, 2004 February-August (Box-folder 4:6)
  - Athletics- ACC, 2004 September-November (Box-folder 4:7)
  - Athletics- ACC, 2004 November-2005 May (Box-folder 5:1)
  - Athletics- NCAA, 2004 August-September (Box-folder 5:2)
  - Athletics- NCAA, 2004 September-2005 January (Box-folder 5:3)
  - Athletics- NCAA, 2005 January-May (Box-folder 5:4)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 5:5)
  - "Ba" - "Bl" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 5:6)
  - "Bl" - "Bm" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 5:7)
  - "Bn" - "Br" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 6:1)
  - "Bs"-"Bz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 6:2)
  - Business and Finance, 2004 July-August (Box-folder 6:3)
  - Business and Finance, 2004 August-October (Box-folder 6:4)
  - Business and Finance, 2004 November-2005 March (Box-folder 6:5)
  - Business and Finance, 2005 March-July (Box-folder 6:6)
  - "Ca" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 4. (Box-folder 6:7)
  - "Ca" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 4. (Box-folder 7:1)
  - "Ca" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 3 of 4. (Box-folder 7:2)
  - "Ca" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 4 of 4. (Box-folder 7:3)
  - "Ca" - "Cg" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 7:4)
  - "Ch" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 7:5)
  - "Ci" - "Cn" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 7:6)
  - "Co" - "Cz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 2. (Box-folder 8:1)
  - "Co" - "Cz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 2. (Box-folder 8:2)
  - Carr's Hill, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:3)
  - Casteen, John T. III, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:4)
  - Charlottesville, City of (Planning and Coordination Council), 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:5)
  - Chesapeake Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:6)
  - Commerce School, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 8:7)
  - Community Relations, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:1)
  - Condolences A-G, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:2)
  - Condolences G-M, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Condolences P-Z, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:4)
  - Continuing and Professional Studies, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:5)
  - Council for Higher Education Accreditation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 9:6)
  - Council of Presidents, 2004 October-December (Box-folder 9:7)
  - Council of Presidents, 2005 January-February (Box-folder 9:8)
  - Council of Presidents, 2005 February-June (Box-folder 9:9)
  - "Da" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 10:1)
  - "De" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 10:2)
  - "Df" - "Dz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 10:3)
  - Darden School, 2004 June-October (Box-folder 10:4)
  - Darden School, 2004 October-December (Box-folder 10:5)
  - Darden School, 2004 December-2005 June (Box-folder 10:6)
  - Development, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 10:7)
  - Drama, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 10:8)
  - "E" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:1)
  - Economics, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:2)
  - Education School, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:3)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, 2004 September-November (Box-folder 11:4)
  - Engineering and Applied Science, 2004 December-2005 June (Box-folder 11:5)
  - English, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:6)
  - Environmental Sciences, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:7)
  - "Fa" - "Fh" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:8)
  - "Fi"- "Fo" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:9)
  - "Fo" - "Fz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 11:10)
  - Facilities Management, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:1)
  - Faculty, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:2)
  - Finance, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:3)
  - Financial Aid to Students' Office, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:4)
  - "Ga" - "Gz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:5)
  - General Assembly, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 12:6)
  - General Assembly- Meeting, 2005 February 1 (Box-folder 12:7)
  - General Assembly- Meeting, 2005 February 15 (Box-folder 13:1)
  - German Department, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 13:2)
  - Governmental Relations, 2004 July-December (Box-folder 13:3)
  - Governmental Relations, 2005 January-April (Box-folder 13:4)
  - Governmental Relations, 2005 May (Box-folder 13:5)
  - Governor's Office, 2004 September-2005 February (Box-folder 13:6)
  - Governor's Office, 2005 February-June (Box-folder 13:7)
  - "Ha"-"Hh" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 13:8)
  - "Hi"-"Ho" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:1)
  - "Ho" - "Hz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:2)
  - History, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:3)
  - Honor System, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:4)
  - Housing, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:5)
  - Human Resources, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 14:6)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 2. (Box-folder 14:7)
  - Invitations to Inaugurations, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 2. (Box-folder 14:8)
  - "I" - "In" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - "In" - "Iz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15:2)
  - Information Technologies, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15:3)
  - Institutional Assessment Studies, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15:4)
  - International Studies, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 15:5)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 5. (Box-folder 15:6)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 5. (Box-folder 15:7)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2004-2005, Folder 3 of 5. (Box-folder 16:1)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2004-2005, Folder 4 of 5. (Box-folder 16:2)
  - Irish Universities Quality Board, 2004-2005, Folder 5 of 5. (Box-folder 16:2a)
  - "Ja" - "Jo" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 16:3)
  - "Jo" - "Jz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 16:4)
  - Jefferson Memorial Foundation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 16:5)
  - Jefferson Scholars Program, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 16:6)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Committee, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:1)
  - "K" - "Ke" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:2)
  - "Ke" - "Ki" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:3)
  - "Ki" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:4)
  - "Ki" - "Ko" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:5)
  - "Ko" - "Kz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 17:6)
  - "L" - "Le" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 18:1)
  - "Le" - "Li" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 18:2)
  - "Li" - "Lz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 18:3)
  - Law, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 18:4)
  - Library, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 2. (Box-folder 18:5)
  - Library, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 2. (Box-folder 18:6)
  - "Ma" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 19:1)
  - "Me" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 19:2)
  - "Mf" - "Mz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 19:3)
  - Management and Budget, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 19:4)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2004 January-December (Box-folder 19:5)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2004 December (Box-folder 19:6)
  - Mariners' Museum, 2004 December-2005 May (Box-folder 19:7)
  - Medical Center- General, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 20:1)
  - Medical Center- Medical School, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 20:2)
  - Medical Center- Nursing School, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 20:3)
  - Minority Affairs, 2004 August (Box-folder 20:4)
  - Minority Affairs, 2004 September-2005 February (Box-folder 20:5)
  - Music, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 20:6)
  - "Na" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 20:7)
  - "Nb" - "Ne" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 20:8)
  - "Nf" - "Nz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:1)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:2)
  - "O" Miscellaneous (Box-folder 21:3)
  - "Pa" - "Ph" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:4)
  - "Pi" - "Pz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:5)
  - Parking and Transportation, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:6)
  - Politics, Department of, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:7)
  - President's Senior Cabinet, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:8)
  - Procurement Services, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 21:9)
  - Provost, 2004 June-July (Box-folder 22:1)
  - Provost, 2004 July-September (Box-folder 22:2)
  - Provost, 2004 September-2005 March (Box-folder 22:3)
  - Provost, 2005 March-July (Box-folder 22:4)
  - Psychology, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 22:5)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 22:6)
  - "Ra" - "Re" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 22:7)
  - "Re" - "Rh" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 22:8)
  - "Rh" - "Ro" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:1)
  - "Ro" - "Rz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:2)
  - Registrar, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:3)
  - Recommendations, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:4)
  - Religious Studies, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:5)
  - Requests for Nominations, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:6)
  - Research and Public Service, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 3. (Box-folder 23:7)
  - Research and Public Service, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 3. (Box-folder 23:8)
  - Research and Public Service, 2004-2005, Folder 3 of 3. (Box-folder 23:9)
  - Reserve Officers' Training Corps (ROTC), 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:10)
  - "Sa" - "Sd" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:11)
  - "Se" - "Sh" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 23:12)
  - "Si" - "Sm" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 24:1)
  - "Sm" - "Sn" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 24:2)
  - "So" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 24:3)
  - "Sp" - "Sz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 24:4)
  - Senate- Faculty and University, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 24:5)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 2004 July-October (Box-folder 24:6)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 2004 October-2005 January (Box-folder 24:7)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools, 2005 January-June (Box-folder 25:1)
  - Sponsored Programs, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 25:2)
  - State Council of Higher Education, 2004 August-September (Box-folder 25:3)
  - State Council of Higher Education, 2004 October-2005 May (Box-folder 25:4)
  - Student Affairs- General, 2004 August-December (Box-folder 25:5)
  - Student Affairs- General, 2005 February-September (Box-folder 25:6)
  - Student Affairs- Dean of Students Office, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 25:7)
  - Student Affairs- Fraternities and Sororities, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 25:8)
  - Student Council, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:1)
  - Summer Session, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:2)
  - "Ta" - "Te" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:3)
  - "Te" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:4)
  - "Tf" - "Tz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:5)
  - "U" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:6)
  - United Way Combined Charitable Campaign, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 26:7)
  - Universities Research Association, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 27:1)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise, 2004 August-2005 January (Box-folder 27:2)
  - University of Virginia's College at Wise, 2005 February-April (Box-folder 27:3)
  - University Police, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 27:4)
  - University Press, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 27:5)
  - University Relations and News Office, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 27:6)
  - "Va" - "Vi" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 28:1)
  - "Vi" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 28:2)
  - "Vi" - "Vz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 28:3)
  - Vice Presidents' Annual Report, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 28:4)
  - Vice Presidents' Planning Documents, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 28:5)
  - Virginia 2010, 2004 October (Box-folder 29:1)
  - Virginia 2010, 2005 January-April (Box-folder 29:2)
  - Virginia Business Higher Education Council, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:3)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:4)
  - "Wa" - "Wh" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:5)
  - "Wi" - "Wo" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:6)
  - "Wo" - "Wz" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:7)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:8)
  - "X" - "Z" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 29:9)
- Series II: Restricted Materials
  - "A" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 30:1)
  - Admissions, 2004 July-November (Box-folder 30:2)
  - Admissions, 2004 November-December (Box-folder 30:3)
  - Admissions, 2004 December-2005 January (Box-folder 30:4)
  - Admissions, 2005 January-February (Box-folder 30:5)
  - Admissions, 2005 February-March (Box-folder 30:6)
  - Admissions, 2005 March-April (Box-folder 31:1)
  - Admissions, 2005 April-June (Box-folder 31:2)
  - Audit Department, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:3)
  - "B" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:4)
  - Business and Finance, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:5)
  - "C" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:6)
  - Condolences, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:7)
  - "D" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:8)
  - Engineering, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:9)
  - "F" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:10)
  - Finance, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:11)
  - Honor System, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:12)
  - "K" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:13)
  - Law School, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 31:14)
  - "M" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 32:1)
  - "N" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 1 of 2. (Box-folder 32:2)
  - "N" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005, Folder 2 of 2. (Box-folder 32:2a)
  - Provost, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 32:3)
  - "R" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 32:4)
  - "S" Miscellaneous, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 32:5)
  - Student Affairs, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 32:6)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2004 July-October (Box-folder 32:7)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2004 October-December (Box-folder 33:1)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2005 March-May (Box-folder 33:2)
  - University of Virginia Investment Management Company, 2005 May-June (Box-folder 33:3)
  - Virginia 2010, 2004-2005 (Box-folder 33:4)